So as I mentioned in the last lecture,
المدرب: كما ذكرت في المحاضرة الأخيرة ، يعتبر
watch mode is a great start
وضع المشاهدة بداية رائعة ولكن
but what if we have more than one TypeScript file?
ماذا لو كان لدينا أكثر من ملف TypeScript؟
What if we also have an analytics.ts file
ماذا لو كان لدينا أيضًا تحليلات. ts حيث نرسل افتراضيًا
where we hypothetically send analytics data to our server?
بيانات التحليلات إلى خادمنا؟
Now, here to just have anything in there,
الآن ، هنا للحصول على أي شيء هناك ،
I'll just put in a console.log statement
سأضع وحدة تحكم. بيان السجل ولكن بالطبع
but of course, you could be sending HTTP requests
، يمكنك إرسال طلبات HTTP إلى خدمة التحليلات
to your analytics service here as I said.
الخاصة بك هنا كما قلت.
So let's say we also did import this file here
لنفترض أننا قمنا أيضًا باستيراد هذا الملف
in our index.html file.
هنا في فهرسنا. ملف html.
If we point at analytics.js here
إذا أشرنا إلى التحليلات. js هنا والتي لم تكن موجودة
which does not exist yet
بعد ولكنها ستكون
but which will exist after compilation,
موجودة بعد التجميع ، فيمكننا إذن تحميل
then we could be loading these two files
هذين الملفين وبالطبع ،
and of course, we wanna compile both files
نريد تجميع كلا الملفين كلما
whenever one of them changes.
تغير أحدهما.
Now, for that, it would be nice
الآن ، لذلك ، سيكون من
if we could enter some general watch mode
الجيد أن نتمكن من إدخال وضع مشاهدة عام
where we just run tsc like this
حيث نقوم فقط بتشغيل tsc مثل هذا
so without pointing at a file
دون الإشارة إلى ملف ويقوم فقط
and it just watches our entire project folder
بمشاهدة مجلد المشروع بالكامل وإعادة
and recompiles any TypeScript file that might change.
تجميع أي ملف TypeScript قد يتغير.
Well, turns out that this is possible.
حسنًا ، اتضح أن هذا ممكن.
For that we just need to tell TypeScript
لذلك نحتاج فقط إلى إخبار TypeScript
that this here is one project
أن هذا هنا مشروع واحد يجب إدارته باستخدام TypeScript
that should be managed with TypeScript
ونحن نقوم بذلك أولاً وقبل
and we do that by first of all,
كل شيء ، ونحتاج فقط إلى القيام بذلك مرة واحدة ، وتشغيل
running tsc --init.
tsc --init.
So I'm not pointing at a specific file here,
لذا فأنا لا أشير إلى ملف معين هنا ،
I just run tsc and then --init here
لقد قمت بتشغيل tsc وبعد ذلك - هنا ومرة أخرى ، هذا
and again, this is only required once.
مطلوب مرة واحدة فقط.
It will initialize this project
سيقوم بتهيئة هذا المشروع الذي تقوم
in which you run this command as a TypeScript project.
فيه بتشغيل هذا الأمر كمشروع TypeScript.
That means it will now basically tell TypeScript
هذا يعني أنه سيخبر TypeScript الآن بشكل أساسي أن كل شيء
that everything in the folder
موجود في المجلد حيث تقوم بتشغيل
where you run this command and therefore it's important
هذا الأمر ، وبالتالي من المهم أن تقوم
that you navigated into the right folder
بالانتقال إلى المجلد الصحيح قبل تشغيل
before you ran this command
هذا الأمر باستخدام المحطة
with the built-in terminal here in VS Code.
الطرفية المضمنة هنا في VS Code.
I'm automatically in this project folder
أنا تلقائيًا في مجلد المشروع هذا حيث
where my files are so that this project
توجد ملفاتي بحيث تتم إدارة هذا المشروع الآن
is now managed by TypeScript.
بواسطة TypeScript.
So let's hit Enter
فلنضغط على Enter وما
and what this does is it creates this tsconfig.json file.
يفعله هذا هو أنه ينشئ هذا tsconfig. json.
This basically is the indicator for TypeScript
هذا في الأساس هو مؤشر TypeScript على أن المشروع
that the project in which this file lies
الذي يقع فيه هذا الملف ويجب أن تتم إدارة جميع
and all sub folders of this folder
المجلدات الفرعية لهذا المجلد
should be managed by TypeScript.
بواسطة TypeScript.
Now, if we have a look into this file,
الآن ، إذا ألقينا نظرة على
we see there a bunch of options,
هذا الملف ، فإننا نرى هناك مجموعة
most of them commented out,
من الخيارات ، علق معظمهم
they're just there so that you see that you could set them
عليها ، إنها موجودة فقط حتى ترى أنه يمكنك تعيينها
and you've got a short explanation here as well
ولديك شرح موجز هنا أيضًا لكن لا داعي للقلق
but we don't have to worry about those right now.
بشأن هؤلاء الآن.
We'll dive into them in a second.
سوف نتعمق فيها في ثانية.
For the moment, let's just close this file here
في الوقت الحالي ، دعنا نغلق هذا
and let's see what this gives us
الملف هنا ودعنا نرى ما يعطينا
because what it does give us
هذا لأن ما يقدمه لنا
is that we can now run just tsc like this
هو أنه يمكننا الآن تشغيل tsc فقط مثل هذا
without pointing at a specific file.
دون الإشارة إلى ملف معين.
And what this will do is it will tell TypeScript
وما سيفعله هذا هو أنه سيخبر TypeScript
to go ahead and compile all TypeScript files
بالمضي قدمًا وتجميع جميع ملفات TypeScript
so all .ts files it can find in this project
لذا كل ذلك. ts يمكن العثور عليها في هذا المشروع ،
so if I hit Enter here,
لذا إذا قمت بالضغط على Enter هنا
you see, this takes a while,
، كما ترى ، يستغرق هذا بعض الوقت ، والآن
and now what we got is this analytics.js file
ما حصلنا عليه هو هذه التحليلات. js وهذا التطبيق.
Now, the analytics.js file was just created
js.
by TypeScript because it found
TypeScript لأنه وجد أن لدينا التحليلات.
and as I said, it will now compile all TypeScript files
ts
in the project.
في المشروع.
And of course, this can also be combined with watch mode.
وبالطبع ، يمكن أيضًا دمج هذا مع وضع المشاهدة.
You can run tsc -w
يمكنك تشغيل tsc -w أو --watch كما أظهرت
or --watch as I showed before
من قبل وسيدخل هذا الآن إلى وضع المراقبة
and this will now enter watch mode for all TypeScript files.
لجميع ملفات TypeScript.
So now whenever I change one of them
لذا فحينما أغير أحدهم وقمت بحفظه
and I save it, it will recompile.
، سيتم إعادة تجميعه.
It will recompile that file
سيعيد ترجمة هذا الملف الذي تم
that changed and therefore, all the reflected change
تغييره وبالتالي كل التغيير المنعكس
in the JavaScript file.
في ملف JavaScript.
And it's now here.
وهو الآن هنا.
If I got back to my page, we see sending data as well
إذا عدت إلى صفحتي ، فسنرى إرسال البيانات أيضًا
because now the analytics.ts file was also compiled.
لأن التحليلات الآن. تم أيضًا تجميع ملف ts.